<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-03-14T17:48:31+03:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">MehrdadLinux Weblog</title><subtitle>Technical diaries</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Troubleshooting the problem of not setting IP on Esxi by DHCP[SOLVED]</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/network/2022/03/14/1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Troubleshooting the problem of not setting IP on Esxi by DHCP[SOLVED]" /><published>2022-03-14T00:00:00+03:30</published><updated>2022-03-14T00:00:00+03:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/network/2022/03/14/1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/network/2022/03/14/1.html">&lt;p&gt;When I want to give an IP to a service, I usually use DHCP Reservation and static the IP value by mac if you are in the ESXI system.
In some cases, you will face the following problem.
DHCP answered the IP request, but the ESXI did not set the IP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Answer :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason for this situation is that in this DHCP server, the default gateway value is not set and only gives the IP
That is why ESXI does not accept this IP from DHCP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you need to make sure your DHCP sets the default gateway value.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">When I want to give an IP to a service, I usually use DHCP Reservation and static the IP value by mac if you are in the ESXI system. In some cases, you will face the following problem. DHCP answered the IP request, but the ESXI did not set the IP.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">how use socks proxy in linux apt</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/linux/2021/01/09/1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="how use socks proxy in linux apt " /><published>2021-01-09T00:00:00+03:30</published><updated>2021-01-09T00:00:00+03:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/linux/2021/01/09/1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/linux/2021/01/09/1.html">&lt;p&gt;Do you need use socks proxy in apt?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is very easy  just&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;open apt.conf in /etc/apt/apt.conf with your favorites editor for example use xed in Linux mint  (If the file in path it is not exist make it :D)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;xed /etc/apt/apt.conf&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and add this code in it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Acquire::http::Proxy “socks5h://your_proxy_server:port”;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Do you need use socks proxy in apt?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sharp or Number sign, that is the question</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/programming/2020/10/08/1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sharp or Number sign, that is the question" /><published>2020-10-08T00:00:00+03:30</published><updated>2020-10-08T00:00:00+03:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/programming/2020/10/08/1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/programming/2020/10/08/1.html">&lt;p&gt;Some people think a symbol in front of C# is Sharp are you agree or disagree?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Years after the introduction of C#, the prevalence of very big mistakes or misunderstand in computer society.
Call # Sharp again of the number sign 
For example when a junior programmer or junior computer scientist saw a # in Twitter some of them call it sharp :O or hashtag
although hash is another name for number sign, you can not call it sharp when you saw it on most of the web.
In this article we are going to discuss, what is different between symbol # we known as the number sign, hash  “#”  and music symbol, sharp, means higher in pitch and we write it “♯” (U+266F in Unicode)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why the Microsoft call it new programming languages C Sharp? Microsoft wants to introduce a higher-level programming language from C++ with more facilities. They looking for new symbols and they find sharp. The sharp symbol is so perfect because it looks like 4 plus ++++
and it means higher in pitch in music. They had a very big problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can not type sharp directly from the keyboard :(.
so they decide to choose hashtag along sharp&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, although we write C# (pronounce c sharp), this # a lonely pronounce number sign or hash&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Some people think a symbol in front of C# is Sharp are you agree or disagree?</summary></entry></feed>